<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<FCI>
  <Context cid="1">
    <question id="1">
      <text>1. Two metal balls are the same size but one weighs twice as much as the other. The balls are dropped from the roof of a single story building at the same instant of time. The time it takes the balls to reach the ground below will be:</text>
      <choices>
        <choice id="A">(A)  about half as long for the heavier ball as for the lighter one.</choice>
        <choice id="B">(B)  about half as long for the lighter ball as for the heavier one.</choice>
        <choice id="C">(C)  about the same for both balls.</choice>
        <choice id="D">(D)  considerably less for the heavier ball, but not necessarily half as long.</choice>
        <choice id="E">(E)  considerably less for the lighter ball, but not necessarily half as long.
</choice>
      </choices>
      <answer>c</answer>
    </question>
    <question id="2">
      <text>2.  The two metal balls of the previous problem roll off a horizontal table with the same speed.In this situation:</text>
      <choices>
        <choice id="A">(A)  both balls hit the floor at approximately the same horizontal distance from the base of the table.</choice>
        <choice id="B">(B)  the heavier ball hits the floor at about half the horizontal distance from the base of the table than does the lighter ball.</choice>
        <choice id="C">(C)  the lighter ball hits the floor at about half the horizontal distance from the base of the table than does the heavier ball.</choice>
        <choice id="D">(D)  the heavier ball hits the floor considerably closer to the base of the table than the lighter ball, but not necessarily at half the horizontal distance.</choice>
        <choice id="E">(E)  the lighter ball hits the floor considerably closer to the base of the table than the heavier ball, but not necessarily at half the horizontal distance.</choice>
      </choices>
      <answer>a</answer>
    </question>
  </Context>
  <Context cid="2">
    <question id="3">
      <text>3.  A potted plant falling from a patio roof on the top of a single story building:</text>
      <choices>
        <choice id="A">(A)  reaches a maximum speed quite soon after release and then falls at a constant speed thereafter.</choice>
        <choice id="B">(B)  speeds up as it falls because the gravitational attraction gets considerably stronger as the plant gets closer to the earth.</choice>
        <choice id="C">(C)  speeds up because of an almost constant force of gravity acting on it.</choice>
        <choice id="D">(D)  falls because of the natural tendency of all objects to rest on the surface of the earth.</choice>
        <choice id="E">(E)  falls because of the combined effects of the force of gravity pushing it downward and the force of the air pushing it downward.</choice>
      </choices>
      <answer>c</answer>
    </question>
  </Context>
</FCI>